Pouriya Zarbafian

Email: pouriya.zarbafian@gmail.com - Website: zarbafian.com

Background

Software engineer and programming expert with a broad experience in software and enterprise architecture; a team player with excellent analytical skills; results-oriented; the ability to work under pressure; dedicated to quality of work and efficiency.

Skills Summary

Design: Object Oriented Design, Enterprise Architecture, REST,

SOA, Data Modelling, XML

Backend developer: Spring, J2EE, Apache Camel, Rust, Python

Web developer: Angular 7, Javascript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3

Databases: PostgreSQL, Oracle, MySQL, Neo4j, MongoDB

Mobile Development: iOs, Android, Xamarin

System Administration: Bash, SSH, systemd, Ansible

Tools: IntelliJ, Eclipse, Maven, Git, Nexus, Jenkins, FindBugs,

SonarQube, Logstash, Nagios

ECM: Capture, recognition, data extraction, data organization,

collaborative work, workflows and business processes

Other: Matlab, Machine Learning, Big Data, IoT (Raspberry and

Arduino), Raft

Research Student

Since March 2021: PhD Student at the University of Sydney

- PhD advised by Vincent Gramoli
- Research in blockchain security, scalability, and fair ordering

Work Experience

Aug. 2017 – Feb. 2021: Principal Software Engineer at Global Jet Luxembourg

- Design of the Enterprise Architecture (ESB, SOA, Camel, JMS)
- ➤ Deployment of the new operational tool for flight planning in partnership with Boeing and Jeppesen: analysis and development lead of the various integrations between the enterprise service bus and the flight planning system (Java, Spring, ActiveMQ, XSD/XML, SOAP, REST, SQL)
- Maintenance of existing applications and development of new features (Java, Node.js, Angular, PHP, SQL, MongoDB)
- Setup of Enterprise Monitoring (Nagios, Logstash)
- Development of tools for software deployment and user administration (Bash, Ansible, SSH)

Jan. 2017 – April 2017: Senior Developer Freelance at Chambre des Députés

- > Review and assessment of existing technologies and architecture
- Maintenance and development of new features
- Migration of existing web applications
- Uses Java EE, Swing, WebSphere

Oct. 2015 – Jan. 2017: Solutions Architect at q-leap S.A. for Luxaviation

- ➤ Led the integration of accounting systems into a business intelligence tool
- ➤ Integration of various business applications via an ESB
- ➤ Migration of subsidiaries to a Salesforce based web-application
- > Development of several ETL jobs
- Used Talend DI and ESB

Jan. - Oct. 2015: Senior Consultant at Hamlet Consulting for SIX Payment Services

- > Designed and developed bank interfaces for the Payment Card Industry
- ➤ Hands on experience with EMV and various ISO 8583 based banking protocols
- Created a centralized logging repository to ensure time saving searches
- > Used JEE, Spring, Maven, REST, Swing, Hazelcast, and Lucene

2010 - 2014: Analyst-developer/Test engineer at IRIS Luxembourg S.A. (Canon Group)

- Designed and developed new features on IRISNext, IRIS' solution for document management (Java, Spring, Tomcat)
- ➤ Participated in the development of cloud solutions for OCR, web scan, and invoice processing (Applet, ImageIO, GWT)
- > Tested and insured quality with continuous integration and non-regression tests
- Validated new functionalities on existing products and new products
- Led and created a multi-level training program for end users, project teams, and developers

2005 - 2009: Researcher at Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology

- Migrated the IT environment of a government institution to service-oriented architecture
- > Applied research in Service Oriented Architecture and Model Driven Engineering
- > Designed and developed data exchange, calculation, and payment
- Used EJB 3.0, JBoss, Oracle, PL/SQL, and SOAP

Education	
2020	Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai on Coursera. Certificate earned on February 11, 2020
2016	An Introduction to Programming the Internet of Things (IOT), a 6-course specialization by University of California, Irvine on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on March 8, 2016
2015	Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera. Certificate earned on November 24, 2015
2002 – 2005	Master's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering from CentraleSupélec, France
2000 – 2002	Associate's degree in Sciences of Matter, Université Paul Sabatier Toulouse, France

Languages

French First language

English Fluent
Spanish Fluent
Farsi Fluent